American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIi. 1897 APS.Archives.IIi APS.Archives.IIi
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, Aug. 5, 1897; 3-1/2x4-1/2; Society of Chemical Industry (Great Britain)
    [London] Printed L. filled in in MS. on postal card 1p. and add. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 6, 1897; 4-1/2x7-1/4; Royal Artillery institution, Woolwich
    A.L.S.: A. J. Abdy 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Aug. 8, 1897; 8x5; Nansen, Fridtjof, 1861-1930
    L.S. 1p. Accepts invitation to speak before APS.
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, Aug. 11, 1897; 9-1/4x6; Pawson & Nicholson
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Binding estimate for Audubon's Birds of America.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 12, 1897; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Naturforschende gesellschaft zu Freiburg i. B.
    Freiburg, A.L.S.: Gerhardt, on postal card 1p. and add. In German Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minas [sic] Hays, Aug. 13, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Wistar, Isaac J. (Isaac Jones), 1827-1905
    [Phila.], Typed L.S. 1p., end. Mutilated Reluctantly accepts appointment to Committee on Magellanic Premium.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 16, 1897; 11-1/4x8-1/2; S.S. McClure Company (New York, N.Y.)
    New York, Typed L. with MS. addition 1p., end. Inquires about publications on Babylonian excavations. Refers to Hilprecht.
  - Letter to [Joseph Baer & co., Frankfurt], Aug. 17, 1897; 3x5-1/4; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., L. on postal card 1p., end. Copy Cannot supply early Proceedings.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Aug. 17, 1897; 10x8; Institution of Mechanical Engineers (Great Britain)
    London, Typed L.S.: Alfred Bache, Secretary 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Aug. 18, 1897; 11x8; Atkinson, I. S.
    Orange, N.J., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 18, 1897; 5-3/4x8-3/4; S.S. McClure Company (New York, N.Y.)
    New York, Typed L. 1p., end. Orders Hilprecht's paper on Babylonia.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 19, 1897; 10x8; Beeber, Dimner, 1854-1930
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Inquires about Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 19, 1897; 10x7-3/4; Nova Scotian Institute of Science
    Halifax, A.L.S.: J[ames] G[ordon] Macgregor 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 20, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Oliphant, R. J.
    Oswego, N.Y., Printed L. on postal card, filled in in MS. 1p., end., and add. Orders volume of Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 20, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Temple publishing co.
    Denver, Colo., Printed L. 1p., end. Offers issues of "The temple."
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 21, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; American antiquarian and oriental journal
    Chicago, Printed notice on postal card 1p., end., and add. Change of address.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 21, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed L. 1p. Sends requested bulletin.
  - Letter to Minnis [sic] Hays, Aug. 21, 1897; 10-1/4x8-1/4; United States. Weather Bureau
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Willis L[uther] Moore 1p., end. Exchange of publications. Refers to Abbe, Marvin.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 23, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922
    Stanford University, Cal., A.L.S. 1p. Is sending MS. of Drake's paper on the coal fields of the Indian Territory. Refers to Ashley, J.P. Smith. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 326-419.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 23, 1897; 13x8; Königlich Preussische Geologische Landesanstalt
    Berlin, L.S.: Hans Levorne 1p., end. and add. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 23, 1897; 5-3/4x8-3/4; Virginia Historical Society
    Richmond, Va., A.L.S.: Philip Alexander Bruce 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Cannot supply publications free of charge.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, Aug. 24, 1897; 10x8-1/4; Abbe, Cleveland, 1838-1916
    Washington, Typed L.S., with MS. additions 1p. Concerns his paper on aurora borealis. Refers to Nansen meeting, Oct. 29, 1897. Discusses exchange of publications with Weather Bureau.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 24, 1897; 10x8-1/2; Geological Survey of Canada
    Ottawa, Printed L. filled in in MS. and S.: John Thorburn 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 24, 1897; 11-1/4x9; Königlich Sächsische Altertumsverein
    Dresden, L.S.: H[ubert] Ermisch 1p., end. In German Cannot supply Neuen Archivs.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 24, 1897; 8-3/4x5-3/4; Naturforschende Gesellschaft in Emden
    Emden, A.L.S.: G. Voss 1p., end. Sending desiderata.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 24, 1897; 3-3-4x5-1/2; Gesellschaft Isis in Dresden
    Dresden, A.L.S.: [Friedrich Heinrich Carl] Deichmüller, on postal card 1p., end., and add. In German Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 24, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Pettegrew, D. L.
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks about McCauley's Egyptian dictionary (in APS Transactions, vol. 16, pp. 1-241).
  - Letter to D. L. Pettegrew, Aug. 25, 1897; 3x5-1/2; Morison, Ella M.
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Quotes McCauley's Egyptian dictionary.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Aug. 25, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Woods Hole (Mass.)
    Woods Holl, Mass., A.L.S.: S. Emma Keith, Librarian 1p. Exchange of publications. Refers to C.O. Whitman.
  - Letter to E[lla M.] Morison, Aug. 26, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Pettegrew, D. L.
    Worcester, Mass., A.L.S. 1p., end. Orders McCauley's Egyptian dictionary.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Aug. 26, 1897; 8x5; China Branch of the Royal Asiatic Society
    Shanghai, A.L.S.: E. T. Williams 2p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Aug. 26, 1897; 8x5; Straits Branch of the Royal Asiatic Society
    Singapore, A.L.S.: Henry N[icholas] Ridley 1p., end. Concerns publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 26, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Gives new address of Sajous.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Aug. 27, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Clayton, Joseph Culbertson
    New York, A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 27, 1897; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Kelly & Walsh
    Shanghai, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Forwards publications of Royal Asiatic Society, China Branch.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 27, 1897; 10x8-1/4; United States. Weather Bureau
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Cleveland Abbe 1p. Inquires about Borough, Discours on... the Compas, 1581.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 28, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Haupt, Alex. J. D. (Alexander James Derbyshire), 1859-1934
    St. Paul, Minn., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Change of address for Herman Haupt.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 28, 1897; 10-3/4x8; Ludlow, William, 1843-1901
    New York, Typed L. 1p. Change of address.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Aug. 28, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Virginia Historical Society
    Richmond, Va., A.L.S.: Philip Alex[an]d[er] Bruce, on postal card 1p. and add. Cannot supply free publications. Refers to R.A. Brock.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Aug. 29, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Sachse, Julius Friedrich, 1842-1919
    Leopard, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his accident.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 30, 1897; 11x8-1/4; American Institute of Mining Engineers
    New York, Typed L. 1p., end. Forwards portrait of P. Tunner.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 30, 1897; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Boston Athenaeum
    Boston, A.L.S.: W[illiam] C[oolidge] Lane 1p. Sends copy of Catalogue.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Aug. 30, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Melville, George W. (George Wallace), 1841-1912
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p. Cannot attend Nansen meeting. Refers to his ship "Jeannette."
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 30, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Pettegrew, D. L.
    Worcester, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. Complains that he has not received his McCauley's Egyptian dictionary.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 31, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Pettegrew, D. L.
    Worcester, Mass., A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting Sends payment for McCauley's Egyptian dictionary.
  - Letter to [Ella M. Morison], Aug., 1897; 9x5-3/4; Castell, F. de P.
    Guatemala City, A.L.S. 1p., end. Sends payment for copy of Brinton's paper on the Cakchiquel Language of Guatemala. Written on verso of Morison to Castell, July 22, 1897.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 1, 1897; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Verein für Thüringische Geschichte und Alterthumskunde
    Jena, Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: Steinhauser, on postal card 1p., end., and add. Asks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Sept. 2, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, Pa., L.S. 1p. Concerns Planned paper on manuscript illumination of the Pennsylvania Germans. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 424-433.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 2, 1897; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Michael, Helen Abbott, 1857-1904
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Change of address.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 2, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Royal geographical society of Australasia. Victorian branch, Melbourne
    Melbourne, A.L.S.: A. C. Macdonald 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 2, [1897]; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Moore, Clarence B. (Clarence Bloomfield), 1852-1936
    [Phila.], A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Offers copies of his reports on Indian mounds in Georgia and Florida.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 2, 1897
    A.L.S. 1p. In German.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 3, 1897; 10x8; Institution of Civil Engineers (Great Britain)
    [London], Typed L.S. with stamp: J. H. T. Tudsbery 1p., end. Asks for A.P.S. membership list.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 3, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Geological Survey (U.S.)
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Cha[rle]s C. Darwin 1p. Proceedings exchange.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 4, 1897; 10-1/4x8; United States. Surgeon-General's Office
    Washington, Typed L.S. J[ames] C[ushing] Merrill 1p., end. Asks for replacement for defective issue of Proceedings.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Sept. 4/16, 1897; 11-1/4x9; Karpinsky, Alexander Petrowitsch, 1846-1936
    St. Petersburg, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Sept. 5, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Historical and Scientific Society of Manitoba
    Duluth, Minn., A.L.S.: L.A. Faulkner 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Sept. 5, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, Pa., L.S. 1p. Concerns paper on Pennsylvania German manuscript illumination. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 424-433.
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, Sept. 6, 1897; 8x5; Royal Society of Victoria (Melbourne, Vic.)
    Melbourne, A.L.S.: A. Howlett 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Sept. 6, 1897; 8x5; Trumbull, H. Clay (Henry Clay), 1830-1903
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Has no copy of J.H. Trumbull's Indian dictionary and vocabulary.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Sept. 7, 1897; 8x5; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    Siasconset, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends letter from R.H. Mathews.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Sept. 7, 1897; 10x8; Institution of Mechanical Engineers (Great Britain)
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Sept. 7, 1897; 9x5-1/2; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    Harrisburg. [Pa.], A.L.S. 1p. Declines to serve on committee on Van Denburgh's paper on the Gila monster.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 8, 1897; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Naturforschende gesellschaft zu Freiburg i. B.
    Freiburg, A.L.S.: Gerhardt, on postal card 1p. and add. In German Concerns shipment of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 8, 1897; 8-3/4x5-3/4; Senckenbergische Naturforschende Gesellschaft
    Frankfurt a.M., A.L.S.: J. Blum 1p., end. In German Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 9, 1897; 10-1/4x8-1/2; Royal geographical society of Australasia, Queensland, Brisbane branch
    Brisbane, A.L.S.: J. P. Thomson 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Sept. 9, 1897; 10x8; Institution of Mechanical Engineers (Great Britain)
    London, Typed L.S.: Alfred Bache, Secretary 1p. Corrects title of W.G. Armstrong.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 9, [1897]; 9x5-1/2; Moore, Clarence B. (Clarence Bloomfield), 1852-1936
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Sends his reports. Asks for copies of Cushing's paper on Florida archaeology. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 35, pp. 329-432.
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, Sept. 10, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Field, Robert Patterson, -1931
    Phila., Typed L.S. with stamp 1p. Concerns J. Van Denburgh's paper on the Gila monster. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 19, pp. 199-220.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Sept. 10, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Price, Eli Kirk, d. 1933
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. As executor of estate of J.S. Price, returns APS Treausurer's accounts and records.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 11, 1897; 9x5-1/2; Curtis, Charles S.
    Madison, Wis., A.L.S. 2p. Asks about Moncure Robinson.
  - Receipt to I[saac] Minis Hays for cash, Sept. 11, 24, 29, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Tatham, W. P. (William P.)
    Phila., D.S. items 3p.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 13, 1897; 11-1/4x9; Physikalisch-Medizinische Sozietät zu Erlangen (Germany)
    Erlangen, L. 1p. In German Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 13, 1897; 7-1/4x8-1/2; John Wanamaker (Firm)
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Estimate for window shades.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 14, 1897; 5-1/4x8; Bowditch, Charles P. (Charles Pickering), 1842-1921
    Boston, Typed L.S. 1p., end. Asks for copy of Cushing's paper.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 14, 1897; 8x5; Davenport, Samuel, Sir, 1818-
    Adelaide, South Australia, A.L.S. 4p. Sends publications of South Australia branch of the Royal Geographical Society. Discusses customs of the aborigines.
  - Letter to J [Sic] Minis Hays, Sept. 14, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Will obtain copy of "Charters and Constitutions of the U.S. and the several States" for the APS.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 15, 1897; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Historical and Scientific Society of Manitoba
    Winnipeg, A.L.S.: E. Jackson1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 16, 1897; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Ballou, William Hosea, 1857-1937
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. Asks for copy of Proceedings, No. 154.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Sept. 16, 1897; 8x5-1/4; United States. Surgeon-General's Office
    Washington, Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: J[ames] C[ushing] Merrill 2p. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 16, [1897?]; 7x4-1/2; Dimock, Susan Whitney
    South Coventry, Conn., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends copy of records of Coventry, Conn., for the library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 17, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Bowditch, Charles P. (Charles Pickering), 1842-1921
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting Sends payment for Cushing's paper.
  - Letter to J. Minnis Hayes [sic], Sept. 17, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Trying to obtain copy of "Charters and Constitutions of the U.S. and the several States" for the APS.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Sept. 17, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    Geneva, A.L.S. 4p. G. Bertin will expedite French exchanges. Death of Price. Rebinding of Leeds 1729 Almanac by Ellis & Elvey.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 18, 1897; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Oberlausitzische Gesellschaft der Wissenschaften
    Göretz, A.L.S.: R[ichard] Jecht, on postal card 1p., end. and add. In German Cannot supply publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 20, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Lea, Henry Charles, 1825-1909
    Cape May, N.J., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Change of address.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Sept. 21, 1897; 8x5; Kane, Elizabeth Wood, 1836-1909
    Kane, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Returns APS book found in E.K. Kane's library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 21, 1897; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Oberhessische Gesellschaft für Natur- und Heilkunde
    Giessen, L.S. Heuser 1p., end., and add. In German Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minus [sic] Hays, Sept. 22, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Field, Robert Patterson, -1931
    Phila., Typed L.S. with stamp 1p. Enc. wanting Sends committee's report on Van Denburgh's paper on the Gila monster. Refers to Drake's paper on coal fields of the Indian territory. For Van Denburgh's paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 19, pp. 199-220.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 22, 1897; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Gesellschaft für erd- und völkerkunde, Kassel
    Cassel, A.L.S.: Carl Hessler, on postal card 1p., end., and add. In German. Has no Annual Reports to send.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 22, 1897; 11-1/4x8-3/4; Königlich Preussisches Geodätisches Institut
    Potsdam, L.S.: Helmert 3p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to J. Minnis Hayes [sic], Sept. 23, 1897; 11x8-1/4; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Cannot obtain copy of the Charters and Constitutions of the U.S. and the several States.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 24, 1897; 8-3/4x6-1/4; Russia. Observatoire physique central
    St. Petersburg, Printed L. filled in in Ms., S.: G. Heintz 1p., end. In French Printed receipt pasted to sheet Receipt of Proceedings.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Sept. 24, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Zoological Society of London
    London, L.S.: P[hilip] L[utley] Sclater 3p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 24-Nov. 3, 1897; Stevens, Benjamin Franklin, 1833-1902
    London, L. 4 items 4p., end. Various sizes. Concerns his subscription to the Proceedings.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Sept. 25, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Field, Robert Patterson, -1931
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Concerns Van Denburgh's paper.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Sept. 27, 1897; 8x5; Mathews, R. H. (Robert Hamilton), 1841-1918
    Parramatta, [N.S.Wales], A.L.S. 4p. Enc. wanting Concerns paper on Australian rock carvings and paintings. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 466-478.
  - Letter to John Hays [sic], Sept. 28, 1897; 11x8-1/2; W.H. Lowdermilk & Co.
    Washington, Typed L. 1p. Quotations.
  - Letter to J. Minnis Hayes [sic], Sept. 28, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Scott, John Morin, 1858-1945
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns Pennsylvania state publication he is trying to obtain for library.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Sept. 28, [1897]; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Good, James I. (James Isaac), 1850-1924
    Reading, [pa.], A.L.S. 2p. Asks about two books. Refers to Saur papers.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minus [sic] Hays, Sept. 29, 1897; 6-1/4x8-1/2; Field, Robert Patterson, -1931
    Phila., Typed L.S. with stamp 1p. Will see him on Friday.
  - Letter to Frederic [sic] Fraley, Sept. 29, 1897; 11x8; Grey, Norman
    Camden, N.J., Typed L.S. with MS. corrections 1p. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Sept. 29, 1897; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Redpath Lyceum Bureau
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 30, 1897; 9-1/2x5-3/4; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Phila., A.L.S.: Edw[ard] J. Nolan 1p., end. Asks about duplicates of journal of Royal Microscopical Society.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Sept. 30, 1897; 8x5; Davis, Allen A.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Sept. 30, 1897; 7x4-1/2, 6-3/4x5-3/4; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    A.L.S. 1p. Enc. of 4p. printed leaflet Sends invitation to Special Meeting of Bucks County Historical Society.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 1, 1897; 11x8-1/4; Historical and Scientific Society of Manitoba
    Winnipeg, A.L.S.: E. Jackson1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Oct. 3, 1897; 9-1/2x5-3/4; Heilprin, Angelo, 1853-1907
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts invitation to Nansen meeting.
  - Letter to the Société de Physique et d'Histoire Naturelle de Genève, Oct. 4, 1897; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: I[saac] Minis Hays 1p., end. Asks for missing publications. Written on verso is reply. See Société to A.P.S., Oct. 17, 1897.
  - Letter to Felix Flügel, Leipzig, Oct. 4, 1897; 11-1/4x9; Königlich Sächsische Altertumsverein
    Dresden, L.S.: H[ubert] Ermisch 2p., end. In German Concerns his transmittal of American publications.
  - Letter to F [sic] G[eorge] Rosengarten, Oct. 5, 1897; 8x5, 6-3/4x8-1/4; Ellis & Elvey
    London, L. 1p., end. Enc. Send bill for rebinding Leeds 1729 Almanac. For almanac, see 529.5/L52/1729.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Oct. 5, 1897; 9-1/2x5-3/4; Heilprin, Angelo, 1853-1907
    Phila., A.L.S. 3p. Concerns arrangements for Nansen meeting.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Oct. 5, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, Pa., L.S. 1p. Asks to have half-tones sent to the Scientific American.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 5, 1897; 8-3/4x5-3/4; Verein für Thüringische Geschichte und Alterthumskunde
    Jena, A.L.S.: K. K. Müller 2p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 6, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922
    Stanford University, Cal., A.L.S. 1p. Inquires about Ashley's paper on the geology of Arkansas. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 217-318.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 6, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Cattell, William C. (William Cassaday), 1827-1898
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Cannot attend meeting.
  - Letter to P. Minis Hayes [sic], Oct. 7, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Bonsall, Amos
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts invitation to attend Nansen meeting, on October 29.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Oct. 7, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.] L. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends Rosengarten's acceptance for obituary of J.S. Price. Refers to Publications Committee.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 7, 1897; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Physikalisch-Ökonomische Gesellschaft zu Königsberg
    Königsberg, A.L.S.: [H.] Kemke, on postal card 1p. and add. In German. Have sent publications.
  - Letter to [James Cheston] Morris, Oct. 8, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Morison, Ella M.
    Phila., A.L. on postal card S. 1p. and add. Asks about copy of catalogue of Peale Stone Age collection for R. Patterson.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 8, 1897; 10-1/2x8; United States. Dept. of the Interior
    Washington, Typed L.S.: John G[riffith] Ames 1p. Receipt of government publications.